Many of us love live music – listening to the singer belting out classics we love to sing along to.
我们很多人都喜欢现场演奏的音乐——听着歌手高声演唱那些我们爱跟着哼唱的经典曲目。
But while it can be lots of fun nodding our heads to the tunes booming out, it can also harm our hearing.
虽然跟着震耳欲聋的旋律点头晃脑十分有趣，但也会损害我们的听力。
Studies suggest that one in ten adults have had their hearing damaged by loud noises or music.
研究表明，十分之一的成年人听力都曾因嘈杂噪音或音乐受到损伤。
So why is loud music damaging, and what can we do to prevent it from harming our ears?
那么，为什么喧闹的音乐会造成伤害？我们又能做些什么来保护耳朵呢？
Inside our ears, there are lots of tiny hair-like cells located in the cochlea.
我们的耳朵内部，耳蜗里分布着许多微小的毛状细胞。
These cells are referred to as hair cells because very small bundles of stereocilia, which look like hairs under a microscope, sit on top of each cell.
这些细胞被称为毛细胞，是因为每个细胞顶端都有一小束静纤毛，在显微镜下看起来就像头发丝。
These groupings of stereocilia can be damaged when exposed to prolonged loud noises.
如果长期暴露在巨大的噪音中，这些静纤毛束就会受损。
Once damaged, these cells cannot respond to sound, and therefore we are left with noise-induced hearing loss – which can be permanent.
一旦受损，这些细胞便无法对声音做出反应，进而导致噪声性听力丧失——这种损伤可能是永久性的。
It can also leave us with a constant ringing sound in our ears, which is known as tinnitus.
此外，还可能导致耳朵里持续出现嗡嗡声，这种症状被称为耳鸣。
So, what sounds are too loud?
那么，多大的声音才算过大呢？
Sound is measured in decibels.
人们用分贝来衡量声音的大小。
The maximum safe level of sound humans are thought to be able to withstand without potential damage is 80db.
人类在不遭受潜在听力损伤的前提下，能够承受的最大安全音量为80分贝。
The bangs or booms of a firework display can reach 120db, the whirring mechanical sound of a food processor can be around 85db, and live music can be around 110db.
烟花绽放时的爆炸声可达120分贝，食品加工机运转时的机械嗡鸣声约为85分贝，而现场音乐的音量则大概在110分贝左右。
If these sounds continue for a long period of time, it puts our unprotected ears at risk.
如果长时间处于这些噪音环境中，未受保护的耳朵就会面临受损风险。
So what can we do to protect our ears?
那么该如何保护我们的耳朵呢？
Firstly, when listening to music, especially while using your headphones or earphones, make sure you keep it at a sensible volume.
首先，听音乐时，尤其是使用头戴式耳机或入耳式耳机时，一定要将音量调至合理水平。
Also, don’t get too close to speakers that are blaring out music.
其次，不要离正在大声播放音乐的音箱太近。
And, if you go to live concerts, why not take some earbuds with you?
另外，去现场音乐会的话，不妨带上一副耳塞。
Finally, if you get a ringing sensation in your ears, it might be wise to speak to your doctor as soon as possible.
最后，如果你的耳朵出现了嗡嗡作响的情况，最好尽快去看医生。
Your hearing is important, but there are some steps you can take to be as safe as possible.
听力至关重要，但我们可以通过一些措施，尽可能降低它受损的风险。